MICHELLE S. WORTHY

 1366 West Borbon Road
 H: 623.444.4444

 Avondale, Arizona 85395
 mworthy@yahoo.com
 C: 480.222.2222

Production Management • Operations Management • Quality Management

Flexible and participative leader with 10+ years of production, parts manufacturing, quality and operations management experience directing the efforts of up to 650+ personnel to maintain and safeguard \$5.5B in assets. Strategic planner who optimizes labor resources and budgetary funds that meet customer needs and deliver high quality services.

Balance meticulous attention to quality and detail with a sense of urgency to get the job done on-time and meet production goals in fast-paced environments. Dedicated to creating a collaborative team environment where each member can develop and play an active role in the operations management process. Well-versed in Lean / Six Sigma theory and operation. Active Secret security clearance.

Areas of expertise include:

- Fault Isolation
- KPI Analysis
- Root Cause Analysis
- Lean / Six Sigma
- Resource Management
- Strategic Planning
- Policy / Procedure Development
- Budget Allocation / Forecasting
- Team Building

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Maintenance Operations (Maintenance Superintendent), United States Air Force

6/2007 to 8/2012

Planned, prioritized and supervised maintenance efforts of up to 684 personnel across 7 specialties. Maintained accountability and safeguarded \$30M in equipment assets. Established short-term priorities and long-term strategic goals. Oversaw staffing allocation and labor management, training, certifications and quality performance program.

- Chaired production meetings and supervised 5 production managers who established priorities, created workflow schedule and allocated resources to meet objectives.
- **Tracked and analyzed key performance indicators** (KPIs) and metrics to detect positive and negative trends, recognize training needs, correct policy or procedure deficiencies and optimize operational efficiency.
- Reduced safety incidents by 45% after identifying the root cause of safety and quality incidents; raised team's awareness and created a focus on the cause of issues with training, communication and accountability.
- Improved quality assurance (QA) pass rates from 76% to 94% on 7,400 annual inspections.
- **Drove high levels of productivity**. Coordinated with USAF engineers on 150+ repair authorizations that prevented work stoppages and kept \$5.5M in critical assets serviceable.
- **Directed several Lean / Six Sigma projects** to optimize efficiency and save valuable operations resources.
 - > Streamlined the periodic inspection process and identified duplicated efforts. Reduced inspection items by 43% and saved 2 days in the inspection process without sacrificing quality or safety.
 - ➤ Piloted and coached Lean process of streamlining the scheduling of corrosion control washes. Identified personnel utilization and flow issues; reduced time by 61% and saved 1,300 hours per year.
 - Applied Lean tools to an inefficient work process in the precision equipment and tool section. Eliminated 80 hours and reduced backlog by 50%

Maintenance Operations Manager (Accessory Flight Chief), United States Air Force

6/2005 to 6/2007

Led a team of 102 personnel across 4 specialties and managed \$166K operating budget. Planned and delegated all maintenance and repair actions and managed resources that supported maintenance operations of 48 pieces of critical equipment. Monitored shift supervision and staff scheduling to ensure daily operations were properly supported.

- **Prioritized and scheduled 9,300 maintenance tasks** and effectively allocated 31K labor hours to achieve equipment availability rates 1.9% above USAF standards and exceed production goals by up to 20%.
- **Transformed an underperforming section** with disciplinary issues to top performers by using motivational leadership, clearly communicated expectations, accountability and quality-focused maintenance practices.
 - ➤ Led team to improve QA pass rates from 54% to 90%+.
 - ➤ Improved accountability of tools and equipment with a standardized turn-in process. Standardized process and procedure to create consistency.



MICHELLE S. WORTHY • Page 2

1366 West Borbon Road		H: 623.444.4444
Avondale, Arizona 85395	mworthy@yahoo.com	C: 480.222.2222

Continued, Maintenance Operations Manager (Accessory Flight Chief), United States Air Force 6/2005 to 6/2007

- Reviewed KPIs and statistics such as maintenance data, quality control and manpower management reports; strategically allocated labor resources to meet workloads, defined root cause of issues and targeted deficiencies.
- **Stewarded \$10.6M of equipment and facilities**; oversaw the effective use of and compliance with preventive maintenance, safety, security and training programs.

Fabrication Operations Manager (Flight Chief), United States Air Force

4/2002 to 6/2005

Supervised a team of 150+ personnel and managed the upkeep, maintenance and accountability of facilities, equipment and tools valued at \$34.9M. Monitored performance, analyzed allocation of resources, evaluated productivity and managed quality to ensure operational efficiency while meeting customer needs and achieving goals.

- Planned and directed the production of providing 40K annual maintenance and repairs, quality customer service, and manufacture of parts for 29 pieces of critical equipment and 850+ pieces of support equipment.
- Ensured all technicians were in compliance with all safety regulations such as OSHA, personal protective equipment (PPE), hazardous materials handling, storage and disposal and FOD.
- **Streamlined the scheduling and flow of maintenance actions**; reduced backlog by 50% with effective time management and prioritization methods.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Wayland Baptist University, Phoenix, AZ

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Professional Aeronautics, Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, Daytona Beach, FL

Associate of Applied Science (A.A.S.), Aeronautics, Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, Daytona Beach, FL

Lean / Six Sigma Logistics Course, United States Air Force

Supervisor Labor Union and Conflict Management Course, United States Air Force

Senior Maintenance Leader Risk Management Course, United States Air Force

12-weeks of Leadership, Professional Communication and Personnel Management Training Senior NCO Leadership Academy / USAF Chief Master Sergeant Leadership Course

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Management Certification, Community College of the Air Force

Active Secret Security Clearance

